agents are emerging as the latest
Battleground in Enterprise AI we're
going to we're going to bring a level of
uh automation capability that the
world's never seen and I love that you
codified it as agents the second which
we've just reached now is reasoners uh
the third is agents and we're not
stopping there and today we're
introducing new agents you can and the
project I've been staying up late every
night working on for many moons this
year is agent. so I think we're going to
live in a world where there are going to
be hundreds of millions of billions of
different AI agents
eventually probably more AI agents than
there are people in the
world AI agents are here the death of
the smartphone has
arrived hundreds of millions of jobs
will soon
disappear in the world as we know it is
about to change forever and most people
have no idea what's about to hit them
but you're different because in the next
60 minutes I'll show you exactly what AI
agents really are how they'll transform
everything we know today
and most importantly how to position
yourself to thrive in this new world
this might be the most important video
you ever watch consider this your
Survival Guide to the greatest
technological revolution in human
history buckle
up the first step in surviving the next
10 years and Beyond is understanding
where we're going so let me first paint
a picture of the future we're headed
towards Flash Forward to 2035 you're
taking your dog for a walk along the
beach enjoying a slow Sunday morning
Midway through you get a notification
it's a text from your partner however
you don't get your phone out to read it
instead it pops up in the corner of your
field of view in the Sleek sunglasses
that you're wearing the text reads hey
babe Lucy knocked over a bottle of wine
from last night it's spilt all over the
white carpet are you able to book in a
carpet cleaner to come in next week make
sure we don't get ripped off like last
time and being the loving spouse you are
you of course say no worries getting
this organized is no deal for you
because you've got backup as you're
strolling along the beach with a
swishing sound of small waves fading in
and out you say out loud hey Amanda
instantly a soothing female's voice
plays through the speakers built into
your sunglasses hey how can I help I
need to book in carpet cleaners for next
week I'm home on Thursday afternoon so
that's the best time I need help getting
a bottle worth of red wine out of white
carpet give me back some quotes please I
want to get a good price sure thing give
me a moment you reach into your pocket
and grab your dog's favorite tennis ball
and putting it into your handy dandy
ball thrower you sling it far down the
beach sand flicking out behind the pup
as it accelerates into the Distance by
the time it returns panting aggressively
with a Sandy wet tennis ball gripped in
his Jaws Amanda Chimes back in I've got
two quotes back I tried five places but
these are from the only ones that are
available on Thursday afternoon the
first one is
$120 and the other is
$140 however the more expensive one has
a four .5 star rating versus a 3.5 star
for the cheaper one which would you like
to go with the cheaper one great let me
get it booked in for you I'll let you
know if I need any further details
you're now at the end of the beach so
you decide to head over to your favorite
Cafe looking over the water you tie up
your dog outside and step into the warm
Cafe making a Bee Line into the counter
while you wait in line you see a
notification pop up in your glasses
booking confirmed carpet cleaning
Thursday 300 p.m. and just like that
you've been able to organize carpet
cleaning while on your Sunday walk
without lifting a
finger now this might sound like science
fiction a personal AI assistant that
understands your needs and takes actions
for you well this exact thing is
happening much faster than anyone
expected the core technology from voice
AI to automation tools already exists
I've spent the last 2 years building and
selling AI agents to businesses and I've
even built an entire SAS platform for
creating these kinds of AI agents and
from this experience with AI agents the
path from where we are now to this
seemingly sci-fi future that I've just
described has become crystal clear to me
over the next decade we'll witness a
complete transformation in how you live
how you work and how every business
operates in a world where everyone is so
stressed about Ai and automation with
mass layoffs dominating the news
understanding what is coming and the
path that lies ahead for us is a
superpower and in this video I'm going
to give you their superpow first I'll
explain AI agents what they are how they
work and why they're so
revolutionary then I'll reveal the four
phases of the evolution from where we
are today to where we'll be in 10 20 and
30 years from now so you know what to
expect from this technology and finally
we'll break down the opportunities that
lie ahead and how you can position
yourself to win whether you want to
build the next Google or Facebook in
this AI Gold Rush or just ensure that
you're lifted up by AI agents and not
replaced by them understanding the AI
agent Revolution is so important because
billions of people are going to be
caught with their pants down unprepared
for the shift that's coming but once you
understand why this revolution is
happening now everything becomes so much
clearer why AI agents are inevitable why
they'll kill smartphones why every Tech
Giant is racing to control them right
now and why they'll create the biggest
wealth opportunity since the internet it
all comes down to a fundamental flaw in
how humans
computers a limitation that's been
holding Humanity back for
decades to understand why AI agents will
change everything we first need to ask
what seems like a silly question but
what even is a computer and sure they
have screens and circuit boards and we
use them to browse the internet but what
do they actually do for us I mean since
AI agents are just the latest and
greatest software that computers run
understanding this question is key to
understanding what the future holds for
us and nobody understood the value that
computers offered Humanity better than
Steve Jobs I think one of the the things
that really separates us from the high
primates is that uh we're tool Builders
and I read a uh a study that measured
the efficiency of locomotion for various
species on the planet the Condor used
the least energy to move a kilometer and
uh uh humans came in uh with a rather
unimpressive showing about a third of
the way down the list it was not not too
proud of a showing for the crown of
creation so uh that didn't look so good
but then somebody at Scientific American
had the insight to test the efficiency
of locomotion for a man on a bicycle and
a man on a bicycle or a human on a
bicycle blew the Condor away completely
off the top of the charts and that's
what a computer is to me uh what a
computer is to me me is it's the most
remarkable tool that we've ever come up
with and it's the equivalent of a
bicycle for our minds and of course
Steve is exactly right just as bicycles
multiply our physical power computers
multiply our mental power they can
handle the tedious work so that we can
focus on what matters think about a
small business owner before computers
that'd have to spend hours manually
tracking inventory writing invoices
calculating the taxes and now computers
handle all of that automatically while
they get to focus on actually growing
their business and so the value of
computers is that all of this freed up
time can get poured back into things
that actually move Humanity forward the
ripple effect of this productivity gain
is everywhere that computers touch you
have doctors who can treat more patients
because computers handle all their
paperwork for them you have scientists
who can analyze vast data sets to make
breakthroughs even faster than before
Engineers can simulate designs instead
of building costly prototypes and
writers can reach millions of readers
without ever needing a publisher and so
this is what computers really are they
are tools that automate the tedious
tasks so humans get to focus on what
really matters but the irony is is that
while computers automate countless tasks
for us we still have to manually operate
the computer itself so every time you
you need to do something on a computer
you first need to plan the steps so you
need to okay how am I going to do this
I'm going to open the app click the
button Etc then you need to actually
execute on those steps yourself you need
to click type swipe drag all of the
steps you need to execute yourself
manually so while we built these
incredible automation machines we're
still operating and controlling them
like some Factory workers from the
1800s and AI agents are about to change
this forever what we're about to witness
is actually a continuation of a trend in
Computing that's been building for the
past 70 years all computers from your
smartphone to your laptop are limited by
one thing and that's how fast we can
tell them what to do we can call this
the input bandwidth of a computer how
much information we can feed into it
through clicks swipes keystrokes and
gestures let's look at this trend
throughout history starting off in the
1940s the first computers used switches
and imagine yet had to flip dozens of
switches just to do some basic math on
them so you could manage maybe about 10
inputs per minute as your input
bandwidth in the 1960s keyboards arrived
so you can now type commands directly
into the computer but you had to
memorize them like some kind of secret
language and so the speed of input
jumped up to maybe 40 per minute and
then in 1984 the Apple Macintosh brought
us point and click and graphic cool user
interfaces and so with this keyboard and
a mouse we could finally hit say 200
inputs per minute then in 2007 the
iPhone made Computing portable but
despite having touch screens we're still
stuck at around 200 inputs per minute so
for the past 15 minutes we haven't
gotten any faster at talking to our
computers we're still limited by our
fingers and even Elon Musk sees this as
a painful limitation for Humanity the
rate at which we can type words into a
phone or a computer just it's very slow
our input is much better because with
the the data rate from vision is many
thousands of times maybe a million times
better than the rate at which we can
output close your eyes and look
somewhere else in the room aside from
whatever device you're watching this
song Now open them and close them again
in that Split Second your brain
processed everything colors shapes
distances movement now if you tried
describing what you just saw over a text
you'd be typing for minutes to capture
what your brain has processed instantly
I'm in my living room there's gray couch
against the wall there's a framed
Mountain picture above it there's a
wooden coffee table to the left so we're
essentially running a supercomputer
which is our brain with dialup internet
connection to send the instructions from
our brain into our devices it's
painfully slow for example let's say you
wanted to buy those fluffy slippers that
your your ex-wife never let you wear
firstly in order to get your fluffy
slippers you need to plan every step to
get there so step one may be okay I need
to head to the Amazon App then I'll need
to search something in the search bar
then I'll need to get Prime delivery
then you'll need to check the reviews to
get the best ones once you have your
plan you then need to execute on every
single one of those actions you need to
unlock your phone you need to find the
Amazon App you need to tap search need
to type in pink fluffy slippers one
letter at a time you need to tap on the
filters toggle Prime sort by rating and
then hit the buy now button that's over
20 different actions just to buy a pair
of slippers on your phone and we do this
hundreds of times daily say if you're
booking dinner there might be 15 or 20
more steps sending an email might be
another 20 steps scheduling a meeting
might be 25 or more and it's all of this
planning and doing in efficiency that AI
agents seek to solve current computers
are highly inefficient got it but what
if we could create the perfect computer
one that truly delivers on the promise
of freeing human potential the ultimate
bicycle for the mind it would need to
firstly understand what you want so you
can instruct it like you were just
talking to a person and secondly you'd
want it to be able to figure out the
steps to do the thing so you don't have
to do the planning anymore yourself and
then You' want it to do everything for
you so no more clicking or typing or
swiping for you to do on your end does
that sound like science fiction because
the technology isn't just possible it's
already here we are standing at the
beginning of something massive a shift
potentially bigger than the internet
itself but of course here's a catch the
same technology that will transform
Computing will also automate millions of
jobs transform entire Industries
overnight and reshape Society itself
this is why every Tech Giant is racing
to control it while Microsoft Google
Facebook are pouring billions into it
why will create the biggest wealth
opportunity since the internet and the
technology at the center of it all is of
course AI
agents what exactly are AI agents and
how will they reshape our world think
about how we use computers to day
practically everything we do involves
using different tools on our devices
when you're writing something you open
your browser to research if you're
managing finances you'll open up Excel
and that's the tool that you're using if
you're scheduling a meeting then you'll
use your calendar app we are constantly
switching between these tools in order
to get things done but this is where
agents are a bit different so instead of
us as humans using those tools AI agents
allow us just to describe to an AI what
the task is and what the end goal is and
then the AI agent plans which tools it
needs to use and how to use them and
then actually does it on its own not
only can they complete the task much
quicker than we can but in theory we
wouldn't even need to know how to use
these tools in the first place and it's
this that makes AI agents so
revolutionary they're not just some chat
bot that you can talk to they're
actually digital workers that can
actually get things
done the first phase of the revolution
is already here they're called text
based AI agents now these digital work
have exploded in popularity over the
past year or so with platforms like open
AI gpts which let literally anyone
create their own AI agents without
coding firstly an AI model or llm which
is the brain that understands your
instructions and plans how to help
secondly it needs tools which are the
hands that let it take actions at apps
and on websites and thirdly it needs
some kind of memory so that it can
remember the past messages and the past
actions that it's take let me show you
how this all works together with two
different examples say I built you a
weather checking agent and you ask it
what's the weather like in New York
firstly the AI brain or model is going
to understand that you want the current
weather in New York then it's going to
use the weather tool to fetch that live
weather data and then thirdly it's going
to give you back the answer which is
pretty basic right just one request one
tool one action but here's where it gets
a bit more interesting say I had a more
complex task of finding a carpet cleaner
you may ask it I spilled wine on the
carpet find someone to clean it next
week this particular AI agent would have
multiple different tools to allow it to
achieve achieve these outcomes but let's
watch how the AI agent can think like a
human and break this task down firstly
it would plan okay well I need to find
cleaners I need to get quotes and they
need to book the best option then it
would use its web searching tool to find
local cleaners then it's going to
reflect okay I found five cleaners now I
need to find their prices then it would
call each of the businesses to get
quotes then it would pause and reflect
again okay I've got the prices I should
also check the quality too then it's
going to search for reviews and ratings
for each of those businesses then it's
going to create some kind of comparison
spreadsheet then it's going to analyze
the results the second option has the
best price to rating ratio and then it
would go ahead and book the appointment
plan act reflect adjust and then plan
again is exactly how humans tackle
complex problems the difference is these
agents can do it much faster with
perfect memory of every detail and so
these tools that agents use are
basically special connections to apps
and websites they like digital highways
that let the AI press buttons and end
information over the internet and we
call these connections apis and they
basically make the entire internet work
through platforms like open Ai gpts and
my own software agentive hundreds of
thousands of people are already building
and using these text based AI agents
daily even without knowing how to code
we even have platforms like agents. AI
by HubSpot that has created the first
social networking platform for AI agents
that allows you to build and hire these
AI agents as teammates to help you get
stuff done at work but we'll touch on
this more later but you get the idea
right text Bas agents are already here
and they take us basically 2/3 of the
way to the perfect computer that we
talked about before unfortunately we
haven't had our first Target of having
natural communication as we're still
having to type it manually into the
computer however we have boxes two and
three ticked off which are planning the
steps as it's going to plan the steps
for us now and of the actual doing and
operating the computer as the AI agent
is now using tools itself to execute on
those steps without us having to do
anything so overall not a bad
start now you might be wondering
what made this leap in Computing
possible after Decades of stagnation in
our communication with computers why has
everything now started to change well
the game changer was the creation of the
large language model or llms which hit
the world stage with chat gbt at the end
of 2022 for the first time humans could
write to machines and be understood and
even have a conversation and we we take
it for granted nowadays because we're
kind of used to these tools but this is
a technological leap that will likely go
down as one of the most significant
Innovations in human history we
literally witnessed the moment where man
and machine could finally talk to each
other and understand one another and
while at first people did just use this
technology for basic tasks like writing
emails or poems companies like open AI
soon realized its true potential since
these AI models understand language so
well they can read instructions for
using tools or apis and take actions
when you ask them to but at the end of
the day with text based agents we're
still typing everything letter by letter
we've cracked this computer language
understanding problem but we're still
limited by how fast we can actually type
and input data into the computer well
fortunately there's a better
way you'll notice a bit of a pattern as
we start to move through these phases
and that's that the AI agent itself
Remains the Same all that's changing is
how we're giving it instructions the
format in which we're giving the
instructions to the agent for
voice-based AI agents we are ditching
the keyboard and speaking directly to
the agent no longer are we restricted by
the speed of our fingers is but now the
speed of our lips this AI voice agent
technology also already exists this year
we have had new models released that can
take audio as an input and respond in
audio also right now anyone can use no
code AI voice agent platforms like synth
flow or AI to create their own custom
voice agent I've got plenty of tutorials
here on this YouTube channel and also
inside my free course if you want to
check those out learning to create your
own text and voice-based AI agents is by
far one of the best things you can do
right now to prepare for the AI agent
Revolution but we're going to cover this
a little bit more later in this video
this voice AI technology however is
still kind of finding its feet outside
of basic things like answering from a
knowledge base getting these voice
agents to do useful things requires
creating a lot of custom tools and while
these tools can be built on no code
platforms also in order to integrate
them into a Flawless system takes a team
of experienced voice AI developers but
that is changing rapidly so let's not
let it distract from just how far we've
come in our search for this perfect
computer computer with these voice-based
AI agents we have ticked off box number
one which is natural communication as
we're now talking with our voice rather
than having to use our fingers and of
course these also do all of the planning
steps for us and it's going to do the
executing steps or doing steps for us as
well so this seems Perfect Right we've
got all of our boxes ticked for our
perfect computer we finally have a
computer where we can tell it what we
want and it does it well we can still do
better the final step in unclogging this
bottleneck between human into machines
is the use of brain computer interfaces
these are devices that hook directly
into your brain to detect electrical
signals in your brain when you think
about certain things these signals are
fed into a super smart computer that can
essentially decode these signals from
your brain and translate them into your
intentions for moving a mouse and
clicking things on a screen at least
initially in the current stages but why
do we need these well just as our
fingers can only move so fast our lips
can only go so fast as well so the
fastest possible way to operate a
computer would be just thinking about
doing something and the computer
executing on it for you immediately so
there's no fingers or mouths involved if
this sounds like sci-fi it's not and
this is where our mate Elon Musk comes
in and we've actually seen the first
successful human Trials of this kind of
brand computer interface technology by
elon's company neuralink where patients
can Now operate a computer by their
thoughts alone the guy who got the first
neuralink implant as a human has even
been playing some civilization Sixx in
his free time with nothing but his brain
power and of course if you can use your
thoughts to play computer games then you
can definitely use your thoughts to
command and direct AI agents so this new
type of input is put onto the exact same
kind of AI agent framework we've talked
about before but we're just changing the
input again to something that takes even
less effort so we've gone from typing to
talking to now thinking and this
essentially allows us to send more
instructions at even faster rate and the
interesting question is would you want
to hook a computer up to your brain and
while I hate to admit it in 30 years
down the line the chance of each of us
having some kind of chip that allows us
to communicate with computers by just
thinking alone is almost 100% at least
in the in the Western World it likely
won't be a drill a hole in the side of
your skull level of invasiveness like
neuralink is and this current form now
but still it's pretty scary thought but
surely this must be as far as we can go
with this brain computer interfaces and
AI agents right well we can actually
still do
better even brain computer interfaces
with AI agents have a limitation and
that you still need to actively think
about what you want to do for the
computer to pick up on it but what if
your AI agent could predict your needs
before you even had to think about them
and this is the final evolution of the
AI agent technology that we will see of
predictive agents so imagine this your
agent notices that you are working late
from the office it knows that you
usually eat dinner around a certain time
and it sees that you haven't already
eaten and so it automatically asks you
if you want to order food your favorite
comfort food to the office on Uber Eats
and by this point we would also be able
to have our round the-clock tracking of
our blood for things like glucose and
vitamin deficiencies Etc so our agent
will also be able to be our personalized
health coach and be tapped into
everything that is happening within our
body and then be predictive and and
trying to help us to optimize our body
and health also this Collision of Health
Tech with AI agents and brain computer
interfaces is another massive change to
day-to-day life for us that promises to
bring greatly increased human Prosperity
if it's done ethically but Health te is
a topic for a whole another video
circling back to our perfect computer
concept with this predictive brain
computer interfaces we've now solved a
problem that we didn't even know we had
and that's step one of needing or
Desiring which is now solved by these AI
production engines and then of course
the planning is solved by the AI agents
and also the doing so we've taken this
to a level that we didn't even know we
could or needed to this portrait of the
future is is unsettling to most I mean
it certainly is to me and the merging of
human and machine through these AI
agents really marks a turning point in
our species story so I'm not really
seeing just another tech bubble with
this AI agent thing we're literally
witnessing Homo sapiens Break Free of
the chains of biological evolution and
their snatching the pen of intelligent
design from nature itself so no longer
must we as a species wait thousands of
years to evolve as a species we're going
to be just one new software update away
from New superpowers through our AI
agents and our brain implants those who
successfully merge with these new
technologies will become something else
entirely like a superior species that's
better adapted to the digital world that
we've created and as for the rest of us
well we're like modern day neand equally
intelligent but hopelessly outmatched by
their enhanced cousins and we know what
happened to them but why does this all
matter like why should you actually care
well it's because through this insane
amount of change that we're going to see
over the coming decades from these basic
chatbots to brain computer interfaces
the AI agent framework itself remains
constant it's only the input type that
is changing so if you're looking for a
technology to place all the bets on for
the next Century AI agents are your best
option and this is why every tech
company right now is throwing everything
they have at this new technology but
it's not just the big dogs who can
benefit from this AI agent Revolution
right so we're witnessing a multi-
trillion dollar industry developing
before our eyes so getting a slice of
the action is actually a lot easier than
you think it's just a case of being a to
grab a bucket and be standing in the
right place to catch a slice of or catch
your FES share but before we get into
how you can actually Hur your right on
this technology to get what you want out
of life we first need to break down how
AI agents will change your personal life
work life and how businesses themselves
will
operate all the mainstream adoption of
these brain computer interfaces will be
the thing maybe 20 or 30 years from now
the next major shift in how we live is
actually much closer and it's already
beginning perhaps the biggest change
will be the death of something that we
can barely imagine living without today
and that is the smartphone our constant
companion of the past 15 years is going
to sort of Fade Into the background as a
radically different way of experiencing
Digital Life emerges so your phone will
be replaced by a personal AI system that
is always with you and accessible
through a new suite of subtle and
intelligent devices that you carry with
you this transformation is being driven
by three technological breakthroughs
that are converging to the same point so
firstly we have ai that can truly
understand and engage in natural
conversation with you like chat GPT you
can imagine Siri but actually competent
and can do complex tasks and remember
all of your past interactions secondly
we have AR or augmented reality glasses
that look like normal sunglasses we've
seen meta just recently release their
Orion glasses with built-in displays and
speakers which is crazy when you see the
the demos that they've done which for
the first time gives us a glimpse into
the future of what these AI glasses are
going to look like and thirdly natural
ways to control computers including SLE
gestures with your hands or Voice or
even eye tracking as well when these
three combine they will create a new
personal technology stack your
smartphone goes from being the number
one computer you use on day-to-day life
to being a hidden Hub that you keep in
your pocket that's basically just
processing things in the background your
Ari glasses provide visual information
within your field of view a watch or a
wristband reads your gestures and your
AI assistant is always listening for
your voice and your commands through
your AI glasses and the microphone
within them or an earpiece and it's
orchestrating everything you want to do
behind the scenes think about planning
dinner with friends so today that means
juggling multiple apps you're going
messages calendar restaurant bookings
Etc but in 2035 you'll simply say to
your assistant let's get dinner with
Mike and Sarah this week your AI
assistant knowing everyone's per
differences and schedules coordinates
with their AI assistant shows restaurant
options to you through your glasses and
then lets you confirm the restaurant
Choice with a couple subtle actions with
your hand or even just eye motions when
the world switches over to this new Tex
stack the social fabric of our world is
going to change because instead of
everyone staring at their phones you'll
just see people walking around with
these Sleek glasses on or little air
pieces and allowing people to stay
present in the real world while the AI
system are handling everything for them
in the background another subtle thing
that's happening which I don't think we
should sleep on is that the
airpods are probably going to become
much more socially acceptable to wear on
a 24x7 basis because of this feature
that allows it to become a useful
hearing aid and I think as it starts
being worn in more and more social
environments and as the form factor of
that shrinks that's when I really do
think we're going to find some very
novel use case which
is you know very unobtrusive it kind of
Blends into your own physical make up as
a person without it really sticking out
but this is more than just a new way to
use technology just think about how
different your life will feel when
you're no longer tackling everything
alone whether you're trying to find the
perfect gift for someone you're trying
to navigate a foreign city or just
handle a stressful situation you're
going to have this hypercompetence
sidekick that knows everything about you
that's available 24/7 to help you in
anything that you need and so personally
I think this will mark one of the
biggest shifts in The Human Experience
since the smartphone and that's the end
of facing the world's complexity and
challenges of life alone everyone is
going to have their own AI agent
companion making life's daily challenges
just a little bit easier to handle and I
mean you have to think about how many
more people this will will turn into
capable human beings and free up parts
of the population that otherwise
couldn't necessarily join the workforce
to be productive humans because they
just couldn't organize themselves now
having this AI system that can actually
help them do stuff that will unlock
foreseeably a chunk of the population
that previously was just unable to
function a modern society because it's
too hectic and I mean I'm sure you know
that even as a as a functioning human it
can feel like quite a lot at different
times in your
life for anyone who works at a computer
from marketers to analysts to managers
the way that we work is about to change
dramatically and someone who is well
ahead of the curve when it comes to the
future of work is Dames sha and he's the
founder of HubSpot a now multi-billion
dollar Tech Giant because I predict that
in the future our teams are going to be
hybrid they will consist of humans like
you and AI agents so let me show you
what the future of work in 2035 looks
like Through The Eyes of an imaginary
character we can call her Sierra she's a
marketing leader CMO at an imaginary
company called Sunday's swimwear which
is an online swimwear brand so SRA is in
at the office she's at work she's just
met with the CEO to analyze and discuss
some of the past month's numbers you're
looking at their sales data and so they
notice that this retro inspired
collection is selling very well to the
younger customers but they also spot
another huge opportunity which is woman
aged 40 to 55 who grew up with more
classic swimwear styles of the ' 80s and
'90s so now that they have this Insight
they need to create a new campaign to
take action on it and 10 years ago this
would have meant weeks of coordinating
with teams and vendors to get a new
campaign put together but in 2035 Sarah
starts by asking her competitor analysis
agent through her air piece write me a
report on how premium swimwear brands
are connecting with women over 40
especially using nostalgic themes in
minutes this agent has analyzed
thousands of ads and websites and
delivers a two-page report showing Sarah
that vintage INSP designs and old school
Beach imagery strongly resonate with
this kind of audience so then Sarah
briefs her creative director agent let's
create ads that capture the Golden Age
of beach culture we can think 1980s
California summer use models in some
kind of vintage style settings that
remind our audience of their favorite
Beach Memories the creative director
agent then orchestrates the rest of the
AI agent team starting with the
copyrighting agent who's going to be
told to write some nostalgic ad copy for
the ads then work with the image agent
to generate some retro style beach
photos then it tells a video agent to
make some ads up with an ad summer Vibe
and then finally it communicates to the
web design agent to build a themed
landing page to run the ads to that
integrates some of the themes that the
competitor analysis agent discovered and
so with this example we can see that
just like how we once said there's an
app for that now our vision for the
future is there's an agent for that and
So within an hour Sarah is ready to
review a vintage themed landing page
from the web design agent 10 new video
ads capturing this perfect summer
nostalgia angle that they wanted to go
for 20 new retro styled image ads and
different copy variations that speak to
the memories of sumers gone past and so
Sarah the CMO now skims over all of
these ads and then picks the best ones
that align with the Brand's image and
their tone of voice the most and then
tells her media buying agent launch
these two women 40 to 55 in the US let's
use $3,000 daily across Facebook and
Google Target people who engage with
vintage fashion content then the media
by agent handles all of the technical
setup on on Facebook and Google ads
automatically and just like that within
an hour they've taken that Insight from
the meeting and taken action and rolled
out a new campaign and for those of you
who are not familiar with the digital
marketing World in order to plan film
and edit all of those new ads in the
current day would normally take weeks
from this we can see that the businesses
of the future will move from insight to
action in just a few hours rather than
weeks by using less people and using
more agents because each company will
get much more leverage from using
software and F people versus lots of
people with a few pieces of software
this isn't about replacing humans it's
about finally delivering on the promise
of computers remember what we said at
the start that computers should be
bicycles for the mind but for years
we've been like Factory workers just
manually operating these computers
typing data into spreadsheets copying
and pasting endless clicking through all
of these menus and now these AI agents
are finally able to do all of the busy
work for us and this is freeing humans
like Sarah to do what they do best and
understanding emotion and memories
making creative decisions for the brand
and using their taste and judgment and
guiding their team of AI agents to bring
that Vision to life this is the future
of work in the AI agent era where this
All Leads is to agents where you can
actually tell the AI to do work for you
you give it an objective it can break
the objective down into tasks and then
it can work each of those tasks so just
like calculators freed us from doing
math by hand AI agents will free us from
manually operating computers the future
of work isn't human versus machines it's
humans empowered by machines finally
free to focus on the work that really
matters if there's pretty dramatic shift
and work concerns you in the next
section I'm going to be breaking down
how to win in this new world of hybrid
Ai and human
teams and finally Beyond just how our
personal lives and work lives are going
to change and the way that businesses
actually deal with customers is about to
transform completely as well and the
first signs of that are actually already
here just like how businesses once
rushed to create websites in theom Era
they're now starting to use AI agents
both internally as we just covered
before but also to talk to customers
It's Beginning right now with simple
text based agents on websites and even
AI voice agents that are answering
phones and these are slowly being rolled
out across the world right now so
instead of a human receptionist picking
up the phone customers call and talk to
an AI that can answer questions take
bookings and handle customer support
questions and we can already build these
today as I said and it's getting easier
and cheaper every single month meta CEO
Mark Zuckerberg sees us as just the
start I kind of think that every
business in the future just like they
have an email address and a website and
the social media presence today I think
every business is going to have a um an
AI agent that their customers can talk
to in the future but phone and chat
agents are just the beginning the real
change comes when businesses create AI
agents that can talk directly to your
personal AI assistant over the internet
as we said any personal life changes
we're all going to have our own personal
AI assistant and just like how
businesses have an email address and a
phone number now that'll also have some
kind of code that allows your agent to
communicate with their customer facing
or outwards facing agent directly as
well when a certain business shows up in
your personal agent search results when
you're looking for a carpet cleaner for
example it can look on their website or
their Google business profile and find
the contact details for the business's
agent and then start to have a
conversation over the Internet with that
agent if you remember how Amanda helped
us to find a caret cleaner before soon
she'll just be able to connect directly
to the AI agents of these local cleaning
companies should be able to conversate
back and forth over the internet to get
quotes rapidly check when they're free
negotiate prices all in seconds without
her having to call over the phone system
as is currently this shift towards agent
to agent communication changes
everything and how businesses reach
customers because when these AI agents
are doing most of the browsing and
searching that flashy websites and ads
become a lot less important and instead
businesses will need to make their
information on their site and about
their business as clear and as
structured as possible so that AIA
agents can understand it easily so
essentially optimizing for AI agents
rather than humans and so digital
marketing itself could potentially be
turned on its head furthermore these
kinds of AI agent interactions makes
everything so much more personal as well
because when your AI talks to the
business's AI it knows your history and
what you like so if you're ordering
pizza or something the AI from the
company or the pizza shop is going to
remember your usual toppings and
delivery instructions Etc if you're
booking a hotel their AI might know that
you prefer High Wars and extra pillows
basically we are moving from Anonymous
transactions to much more personalized
ones through the use of our personal AI
agents egl Siri that comes now iPhone
but on steroids that's capable of
talking to the public agents of
businesses on our behalf every
interaction will be tailed just for you
even when you're buying from companies
with millions of customers so it's
really personalization at scale and it's
the businesses that Embrace this that
make themselves easy for AI agents to
work with and move towards more
personalized experiences that will win
longterm and those that stick to the old
websites and call centers will likely be
left behind so the future isn't going to
be about who has the best website it's
about who is the most helpful and
friendly AI agent that's really to serve
customers through our own personal AI
assistance that'll likely come through
our
phones all right so now you understand
where we're headed took a lot of
explaining but we got there eventually
and so the world of 2035 should be
pretty damn crystal clear in your minds
ey by now but the question now is
knowing all of this how do you position
yourself ahead of time to be able to
thrive in this new world with so much
changing around us how can you navigate
this stormy period like a skilled sailor
and the strategy used to navigate this
period will entirely depend on where
you're in in life and the career path
you're on so let's break down the steps
to survive into four key groups firstly
we have students and young adults
secondly we have entrepreneurs and
business owners thirdly we have office
workers and finally we have manual
workers But first you need to understand
this truth that applies to everyone
regardless of where you are in life and
that's that those that prepare now will
Thrive and those who deny reality will
struggle it's really that
simple so starting off with the young
ones like me those of you who are maybe
18 to 25 you have been handed the
opportunity of a century if you think
about say Steve Jobs he didn't just
succeed because he was brilliant he was
born in 1955 and hit the perfect moment
to be able to catch the personal
computer or PC Revolution he was a
21-year-old College Dropout when he and
Steve wasak started Apple in a garage
together if he was born 10 years earlier
or later then Apple might never have
even happened you can look at Steve Jobs
whole generation you got Bill Gates in
1955 Larry Allison in 1944 Michael D in
1965 they all caught the same wave their
companies Apple Microsoft Oracle Dell
they dominated because they were young
hungry and perfectly positioned when
personal Computing exploded so it's very
much timing based yes they were
brilliant of course but they did catch
the way at the right time and we're at
that same inflection point now with AI
this is your moment just like theirs was
the PC Revolution yours can be the AI
Revolution While others see uncertainty
you should see possibility cuz you have
the chance to become the architects of
Humanity's next chapter but here's the
trap to avoid traditional education is
designed for a world that is
disappearing spending 4 to 7 years
specializing in one narrow field is by
far the riskiest move you can make right
now as a young person things are moving
so fast you you can't be certain about
the future of any career these days
instead your strategy should be to
position yourself at the center of this
revolution learn to build and manage AI
agents Master the AI automation skill
set whether you want to learn how to
code when for me it only took me a few
months to learn the basics or if you'd
rather stick to one or or a few of the
many incredible no code AI automation
platforms that are out there there are
all the tools and all the knowledge out
there that you need to get started in
building and managing AI agents but it's
so important to keep in mind that this
stuff moves so fast you you're not going
to find some kind of college course on
it you have to roll up your sleeves and
and you have to find this information
for yourself online and if you want to
have a solid foundation to get started I
have an entire free course to learn
these skills in my free school Community
once you have these skills you have two
paths soon every company is going to
need one or more of these AI automation
Specialists you can with these skills go
and join these companies and get paid
big bucks to help them with it or if
you're more entrepreneurial you can
start your own AI automation agency and
help businesses to make the transition
into the AI era so I dropped out of
University to pursue entrepreneurship
full-time back in 2020 and I started my
own AI business Journey with the second
option which is building and selling AI
agents and other AI systems as well to
businesses through my agency Morningside
AI for those who are already on the
entrepreneurial path we are at a pivotal
moment and your path forward depends
entirely on where you are starting we
can break the entrepreneurial class into
two distinct groups firstly we have the
AI entrepreneurs these are people are
looking to profit directly from the AI
Revolution just like in California and
the Gold Rush the biggest winners
weren't the miners looking for gold they
were the ones selling the shovels it's
pretty cliche at this point but in this
case in the AI Revolution the gold are
the productivity gains that businesses
are chasing from AI as an AI
entrepreneur you're going to be selling
the shovels to help businesses look for
that gold as Zuckerberg said every
business in the future just like they
have an email address and a website and
a social media presence today is going
to have an AI agent that their customers
can talk to this increasing demand for
AI tools education and AI development
services is the shest BET out right now
for aspiring AI entrepreneurs three
massive opportunities Stand Out firstly
AI automation agencies so this is an
online business model that helps other
businesses to implement AI systems and
as David saaks notes you can't just
throw and llm at these large Enterprises
you do have to go in there and integrate
with your existing systems you need to
map the workflows ETC and this is
exactly how I started building and
selling AI Automation Services to
businesses through my own AI automation
agency secondly you have ai education so
teaching businesses and individuals how
to use and Implement Ai and the demand
for AI knowledge is is exploding as
expected but the supply of capable and
credible teachers is still small right
now so this is a massive opportunity to
help people to understand AI better and
thirdly we have ai software products or
AI SAS this is building the tools and
platforms that businesses need to make
this transition into the AI H in the
future companies are going to get a lot
more leverage from using lots of
software and a few people versus lots of
people with a few pieces of software
there is a surging demand for specific
AI tools and agent systems that can
automate certain parts of specific types
of businesses and this is really the key
here for AIS SAS is that being laser
focused is really where the money is in
AI SAS right now and now as for the
three different AI business models this
stuff does work because as an AI
entrepreneur myself I'm running all
three of these kinds of businesses and
in the past year I've rode this wave of
AI entrepreneurship from literally a
business started out of my spare bedroom
to recently moving back here to Oakland
New Zealand and opening my first office
and we have over 40 staff on payroll so
I've had sort of meteoric success and
these three business models is exactly
what I've used to get there we are still
so early to all of these opportunities
now for the second group of the
entrepreneurial class what we can call
existing business owners so if you
already run a traditional business in
any kind of industry you're facing
essentially an existential threat within
the next 10 years or so because every
industry is going to have these AI first
competitors that pop up just like how
the worldwide web came out and
e-commerce Etc and kind of flipped
certain industries on the head when
people came in and said hey look the
these book stores are pretty inefficient
why don't I just make a bookstore online
oh let's call it Amazon and now we have
of course Amazon so in the same way that
the web and and certain Technologies
enable people to flip the business model
on its head the exact same thing is
going to happen with AI where certain
people come in and look at the current
business that you are running right now
and go hm how can I rethink this from
the ground up by using far more
efficient AI systems in every Department
of the business so these businesses are
essentially going to be operating with
smaller teams leaner teams they're going
to have much more personalized marketing
as we went over earlier and overall
because they're using AI for everything
they're going to have much lower costs
and so your mission as a business owner
now is pretty clear and that's to become
the AI first version of your business
before someone else does and this means
building in-house AI expertise whether
that's yourself as a founder or CEO or
bringing in AI automation experts and
then you need to rethink your core
processes from the ground up with AI and
start doing some pilot tests exploring
the options uh so that you're not caught
on the back foot when they do come out
and start looking into how you can use
AI to scale up the personalization of
your marketing Chi mention if you're a
business owner and any of that stuff
sounds remotely interesting you can
either choose to work with myself and my
agency we build those systems zelfa
businesses and we also do Consulting my
link will be down below but if you want
to hop into my free school Community
there are thousands and thousands of
other AI automation agency owners in
there so by far the best place on the
internet right now to find this kind of
AI help for businesses is within that
free community so the first link in the
description we be able to take you in
there once you're inside you can make an
introduction about you and your business
in the introductions tab then also make
a post in the hiring and For Hire
section and let the community know what
you're looking for and so if it wasn't
already obvious the winners in the
business and and traditional business
category here will be those who Embrace
this change it's not really rocket
science and the losers will be those who
wait until your industry is disrupted by
an AI first competitor and they're
caught on the back
foot for office workers particularly
those in knowledge work and that's in
jobs that primarily involve the handling
and processing of information rather
than of physical Goods you are in the
danger zone I mean look at what's
happening already today you can use 01
and describe or just feed at the data
and describe the analysis you want to
get out of that data and within a few
minutes and I've now done this probably
a dozen times in the last week with
different projects internally at my
company it gives you the entire answer
that an analyst would have taken days to
put together for you what you must keep
in mind is that all of the routine task
all of the lwh hanging fruit of
knowledge work and all computer and
office work that's soon going to be
automated so this is things like
research we've got data injury you've
got data analysis basically any kind of
administrative task you can think of
writing task creative work work like
design like image Generation video
generation music generation basic kinds
of content creation and of course things
like customer support as well you get
the message all of these kind of lwh
hanging fruit and from this the message
is pretty clear your employer will
either give you AI agents to handle
these tasks that can now be done by Ai
and then expand your responsibilities to
sort of fill up your role or they'll
just eliminate your position entirely
and if you hadn't realized it already
there's an entire class of new AI
entrepreneurs starting these AI autom
agencies that are coming to help
businesses to build these efficient AI
agents that will ultimately replace you
and David Sachs explains this very well
it's assembly lines of people doing very
complicated knowledge work but
ultimately you can unravel exactly what
the chain is there The Chain of Thought
that goes into their decisions it's it's
very complicated and that's why you have
to have humans doing it but you could
imagine that once system integrators or
or Enterprise SAS apps go into these
places go into these companies they
integrate the data and then they map out
the workflow you could replace a lot of
these steps in the workflow with agents
and all of this means that you have two
paths forward one is to become your
Department's AI expert this means you
need to be able to learn to build and
manage AI agents you need to learn to
use no code platforms you need to
position yourself as the bridge between
the old and the new ways of working the
these new hybrid teams of AI agents and
humans be the person who knows how to
get the most out of these new tools and
then your second option is to try and
move into roles that AI cannot easily
replace that's things like client
relationship management particularly for
the bigger the client the B where you
wouldn't want to put an AI on
communicating with the client things
like strategy development things like
creative Direction and using your taste
and eye your project leadership for
large projects and generally just
judgment based decision- making where
you are using your experience and
judgment or taste to make a decision
about what the business does and if you
choose to try and become your department
or your business's AI expert then you
need to follow the same path as the
students and young people that we
discussed earlier and that's
self-directed learning about AI
automation the good news is that there's
never been more information available
about how to build and news these AI
agents as I said you can start with my
free course in the school Community I
also have a complete guide to building
AI agents here on YouTube it's like an
hour and a half long best intro to AI
agents on the instent if I do say so
myself uh the link for that will also be
in the description below and of course
there are dozens of other great creators
who are also sharing the knowledge on
this AI automation topic as well but
office workers need to remember this now
cliche AI truth and that AI won't
replace you but someone using AI will
and while that is so overused it is true
the winners of this transition are going
to be those who will Embrace using these
tools to learn and and learn to work
alongside them and the losers will be
the ones who just wait until their job
disappears for the manual workers you
out of all of the groups are the ones
with the most Runway So Physical jobs
are safe until robotics catches up with
AI which is is still a few years away
right now but we have companies like
Tesla and other a bunch of companies out
of China that are showing improvements
in humanoid robots who could very soon
start to replace some of the most basic
jobs that humans do for manual work so
you can't get comfortable unfortunately
is what I'm trying to say so looking
ahead the next 5 10 years you have three
options to prepare and that's you can
position yourself to benefit from the AI
automation boom so you can start
specializing as a robot technician or a
robot specialist there are going to be
many new roles that are created by this
takeover of manual work by robotics you
can start now to try to position
yourself to be one of the winners from
that transition secondly you can try to
use your Hands-On specific experience
and knowledge of the industry you work
in to help lead the transformation into
automation within your industry so that
might mean try to partner up with the
company or partner up with some
developers or robotics engineers saying
look I understand the needs of this
industry think we can build a robotic
solution to create some value and build
a business around it or thirdly you can
try to move into a role that uses skills
that robot still struggle with which is
like complex problem solving or human
interaction but if it's just like
gardening or moving boxes
around there's not much you can do while
your job is safe today the world is
changing rapidly and so use this time
these next few years to prepare not to
pretend that this change isn't going to
come and so it is safe to say that the
coming decades will be unlike anything
we've seen in human history and some see
danger others see opportunity but the
truth is that it's both we're standing
out AC Crossroads and behind us is
200,000 years of slow biological
evolution as Homo sapiens as a species
and ahead of us is this explosive
technological enhancement and the birth
of a new species of superhuman and so
this video isn't about just surviving
it's about thriving in a world where
humans and machines merge where AI
agents become closest Partners where
individual creativity meets unlimited
computational power yes there will be
disruption yes there will be resistance
yes there will be those who are left
behind but you won't be one of them
right because now you see it you can see
it coming that's the whole point of this
video was to give you that Clarity and
that superpower of being able to see
what's coming first now you understand
the path that's lies in front of us
sometimes I have to step back and try to
remind myself just how insane this
moment in history
we are the generation that's going to
witness like the end of traditional
human work with computers doing
basically all of it for us we're going
to see the death of smartphones and the
birth of these AI Companions and so when
our grandchildren ask us about this time
when they ask us what it was like to
live through the greatest transformation
in in human history when they ask how we
handled the transition from Human to
superhuman what will you tell them that
you saw it coming and you took action or
you waited until it was too late the
choice of course is yours but remember
that history doesn't care if you're
ready it moves forward regardless and
the AI agent Revolution is coming it's
here right now and the only question is
which side of History will you be
on what's the best piece of advice he
ever gave you I think Peter was the
person who who told me this really pithy
quote that in a world that's changing
so quickly the biggest risk you can take
is not taking any risk